BARTOSZ KOWAL

(+353) 87 9741 029 * bartek@kowal.agency

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Diligent Software Engineering Student with extensive knowledge of the graphic design and sign making industry. Received multiple awards regarding education. Great range of skills adaptable to any work environment. Experienced in customer service involving exemplary project management and team communication. Eager and motivated to learn and develop in new areas.

EDUCATION

BSc Computer Science & Software Engineering

Sept 2020 - Apr 2024

· Maynooth University, Co. Kildare

Secondary School Sept 2015 – June 2020

Cnoc Mhuire Granard, Co. Longford

Leaving Certificate:

English	Н2
Gaeilge	05
Mathematics	Н4
Spanish	Н1
Applied Mathematics	Н5
Physics	Н3
Construction Studies	Н1
Polish	Н1
Design and Communication	Н1
Graphics	

Points: 579

Weekend School (Polish language school)

Sept 2008 - June 2020

- Szkoła Polska im. Ireny Sendlerowej, Co. Cavan
 - Also attended additional Polish language lessons for Leaving Certificate

Grades: Polish - Very Good, Polish History - Very Good, Math - Very Good.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Maynooth University Entrance Scholar 2020
- Cnoc Mhuire Granard High Achievers 2020

WORK HISTORY

Designer/Signmaker (Full-time)

June 2021 – Sept 2021

· Longford Signs Ltd, Co. Longford

Advertising agency specializing in sign manufacturing and vehicle wrapping. Offering advertising solutions for all businesses, both big and small.

Well-versed in many areas, such as the design, manufacture and installation of signs.

Design responsibilities consisting of the following:

- Detail oriented communication with clients in order to produce designs of maximum accuracy.
- Conceptualize possible solutions to intricate design problems.

- Accurate project plan documentation to ensure smooth project management.
- Ensuring successful collaboration on projects with co-workers through interpersonal skills and excellent communication.
- Proficiency in the following: Microsoft Office, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Suite.
- Strong administrative skills working with (among others) Microsoft Excel and data entry, keeping track of clients and detailed records of projects.
- Client updates consisting of sending project proofs/examples and amending necessary changes.
- Adhering to privacy and data protection policies.
- Strict time-management to meet deadlines.
- Knowledge of the manufacture process in order to align the design process accordingly, ensuring successful assembly.
- Knowledge of printing media (material types, vinyl types, laminate variants etc.), printers/machinery (CNC, Flatbed, Roll etc.) and adjusting design project accordingly.

Manufacture responsibilities consisting of the following:

- Extensive knowledge of material usage based on project size, quality and type. Dealt with Coriiboard, Opal, Acrylic, Foamex, Dibond, Vehicle Wraps, Orafol Vinyls and Laminates.
- Fully trained to use the following: Flatbed printer, Roll printer, Plotter, CNC, Laminator.
- Performing maintenance on machinery.
- Proficiency in Roland VersaWorks/SignLab.
- Fully trained on sign making with wide knowledge of printing media and adequate assembly.
- Trained in window tinting, vehicle vinyl wrapping, partial wrapping, decal application, visor assembly.
- Lightbox design, manufacture and assembly training.

Installation responsibilities consisting of the following:

- Completed manual handling training.
- Area preparation prior to sign installation, adequate vehicle surface preparation when applying vehicle graphics.
- Knowledge and operation of light and heavy hand tools and power tools.
- Assist in erecting scaffolding, ladders and temporary structures.
- Perform general maintenance and adequate waste disposal to ensure a safe workplace environment.

Designer/Signmaker (Part-time)

June 2020 – Sept 2020

• Longford Signs Ltd, Co. Longford (same as above).

Designer (Internship)

June 2019 - Sept 2019

Longford Signs Ltd, Co. Longford
Internship position as Longford Signs as a designer (responsibilities listed above).

REFERENCES

Provided on request.